<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kaspar Rufibach on Kaspar Rufibach</title>
    <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kaspar Rufibach on Kaspar Rufibach</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/1900_template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/1900_template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before going BIG - seize opportunities for small data: use of multistate models to improve decision-making and effect quantification in clinical trials</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2019_roes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2019_roes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implications of the ICH E9 estimand addendum on how we develop, run, and analyze clinical trials</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2019_ct_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2019_ct_europe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rpact - R Package for Adaptive Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2019_psi_webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2019_psi_webinar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybercriminal decision-making</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/teaching/cybercrime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/teaching/cybercrime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Existing theories assume that offenders make rational decisions, but these theories have rarely been tested experimentally. This project uses &amp;lsquo;honey accounts&amp;rsquo;, online accounts that have deliberately been rendered vulnerable to hacking, to allow an experimental investigation of cybercriminals&amp;rsquo; behavior. The research offers unique opportunities for conducting a stringent test of existing criminology theories on offenders&amp;rsquo; decision-making behavior. This study of offender behavior will broaden our understanding of cybercrime, as previous research has tended to focus on victims and security.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Across the Urban Landscape</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/teaching/risk-urban/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/teaching/risk-urban/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parameters of Risk Across the Urban Landscape (PRAUL) uses data from multiple years on victimizations, crime risk factors, and victimization surveys to analyze these causal links between criminogeneity, fear of crime, and actual crime for the city of Amsterdam. Spatio-temporal clustering and regionalization procedures are used to identify areas of elevated risk and delineate analytical sub-regions that are as homogeneous as possible for the theoretical constructs of interest. These newly defined areas serve as units of analysis to study the interplay between the purported crime risk factors, crime, and the public’s reaction to crime and policing from a spatio-temporal perspective. The project aims to provide new insights into the relative importance of individual- and area-level causal factors of fear of crime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risky Business</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/teaching/risky-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/teaching/risky-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do businesses (e.g. bars or supermarkets) and facilities (e.g. libraries) generate or prevent crime? Urban planners and policy-makers often view businesses and facilities as a panacea to social problems: they create jobs and invest in their buildings and immediate surroundings. In contrast, and supported by most empirical research findings, environmental criminologists argue that crime is more likely to occur near businesses. However, such empirical research is based on cross-sectional data, which allows investigating correlation between businsses and crime. However, correlation does not imply causation. So, should urban planners combine residential and commercial buildings within neighborhoods? This project investigates the causal effect of businesses and facilities on crime using unique longitudinal data and recently developed econometric methods for spatio-temporal analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for a crime</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/teaching/time-for-crime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/teaching/time-for-crime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why do offenders commit crimes where and when they do? Improving on extant theory and empirical research in the geography of crime, the proposed PhD-research will investigate how offenders&amp;rsquo; time-specific knowledge of their environment acquired during their daily routines and the time-varying attractiveness of target areas affect offenders’ crime location choices. Combining police-register data on offenders and their offenses with unique data on the locations the offenders frequently visit and data on opening and closing hours of Dutch businesses and facilities, this cutting-edge research project not only advances scientific knowledge, but also contributes to better crime forecasting and urban planning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bpp</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/bpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/bpp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Implements functions to update Bayesian Predictive Power Computations after not stopping a clinical trial at an interim analysis. Such an interim analysis can either be blinded or unblinded. Code is provided for Normally distributed endpoints with known variance, with a prominent example being the hazard ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/package=bpp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download bpp from CRAN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10543406.2014.972508&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pst.1764&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cranlogs.r-pkg.org/badges/bpp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SurvRegCensCov</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/survregcenscov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/survregcenscov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main function of this package allows estimation of a Weibull Regression for a right-censored endpoint, one interval-censored covariate, and an arbitrary number of non-censored covariates. Additional functions allow to switch between different parametrizations of Weibull regression used by different &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.r-project.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; functions, inference for the mean difference of two arbitrarily censored Normal samples, and estimation of canonical parameters from censored samples for several distributional assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/package=SurvRegCensCov&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download SurvRegCensCov from CRAN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1402.0432&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Technical report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cranlogs.r-pkg.org/badges/SurvRegCensCov&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EFSPI regulatory statistics working group</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/efspi_regstat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/efspi_regstat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The regulatory committee of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.efspi.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;European Federation of Statisticians in the Pharmaceutical Industry&lt;/a&gt; (EFSPI) co-ordinates regulatory activities across the European Pharmaceutical Statistical community. The key areas of engagement are the Review of regulatory guidance to provide consolidated cross industry responses and identification regulatory statistical issues that are concern across industry for discussion with regulators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.efspi.org/EFSPI/About_EFSPI/Working_Groups/EFSPI/About_EFSPI/Working_Groups.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More details on EFSPI webpage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>logconcens</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/logconcens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/logconcens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on right or interval censored data, compute the maximum likelihood estimator of a (sub)probability density under the assumption that it is log-concave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/package=logconcens&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download logconcens from CRAN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1214/14-EJS930&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/0707.4643&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Technical report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cranlogs.r-pkg.org/badges/logconcens&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>logcondiscr</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/logcondiscr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/logcondiscr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given independent and identically distributed observations X(1), &amp;hellip;, X(n), allows to compute the maximum likelihood estimator (MLE) of probability mass function (pmf) under the assumption that it is log-concave, see Weyermann (2007) and Balabdaoui, Jankowski, Rufibach, and Pavlides (2012). The main functions of the package are &amp;lsquo;logConDiscrMLE&amp;rsquo; that allows computation of the log-concave MLE, &amp;lsquo;logConDiscrCI&amp;rsquo; that computes pointwise confidence bands for the MLE, and &amp;lsquo;kInflatedLogConDiscr&amp;rsquo; that computes a mixture of a log-concave PMF and a point mass at k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.r-project.org/package=logcondiscr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download logcondiscr from CRAN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/rssb.12011&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cranlogs.r-pkg.org/badges/logcondiscr&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The block criterion for multiscale inference about a density, with applications to other multiscale problems</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/publication/stats_articles/2010-01-02_the_block_criterion_/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/publication/stats_articles/2010-01-02_the_block_criterion_/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- More detail can easily be written here using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biostatUZH</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/biostatuzh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/biostatuzh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Various functions developed at the Department of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebpi.uzh.ch/en/aboutus/departments/biostatistics.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Biostatistics, Epidemiology, Biostatistics and Prevention Institute&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uzh.ch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;University of Zurich&lt;/a&gt;. Currently implemented topics:&lt;br&gt;
- several CI&amp;rsquo;s for proportions,&lt;br&gt;
- several CI&amp;rsquo;s for diagnostic tests,&lt;br&gt;
- Fagan-Nomogram,&lt;br&gt;
- bootstrap CI&amp;rsquo;s for the kappa coefficient,&lt;br&gt;
- intraclass-correlation coefficients including CI&amp;rsquo;s,&lt;br&gt;
- agreement for continuous measurements (Bland-Altman plot),&lt;br&gt;
- CI for the area under the curve (AUC),&lt;br&gt;
- Mantel-Haenszel estimator,&lt;br&gt;
- Mantel-Cox hazard ratio estimator,&lt;br&gt;
- CI for the Kaplan-Meier estimate at given time points,&lt;br&gt;
- CI for quantile of a Kaplan-Meier or cumulative incidence estimate,&lt;br&gt;
- sample size computations for two-sample Mann-Whitney test, McNemar test, binary diagnostic test (via normal approximation and simulation), &lt;br&gt;
- natural re-parametrization of Weibull output from survreg,&lt;br&gt;
- hazard ratio and event time ratio interpretations,&lt;br&gt;
- a plot to check the adequacy of the Weibull model. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ebuzh.r-forge.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
