<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kaspar Rufibach on Kaspar Rufibach</title>
    <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kaspar Rufibach on Kaspar Rufibach</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing for similarity in area-based spatial patterns: Andresen&#39;s test, critique, and improvements (keynote)</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2018-cgca/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2018-cgca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning: What&#39;s it all about? A comparison to conjunctive analysis of case configurations as a case in point</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2018-ecca/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2018-ecca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lorenzgini: generalized Gini for sparse data situations</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/lorenzgini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/software/lorenzgini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wsteenbeek/lorenzgini&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;lorenzgini&lt;/a&gt; is an R package that calculcates the standard Gini coefficient as well as the generalized coefficient, and plots Lorenz curves. The Lorenz plots show the line of maximal equality given the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The package builds on &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10940-016-9324-7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; in which Wim Bernasco and I wrote that the crime and place literature lacks a standard methodology for measuring and reporting crime concentration. We suggested that crime concentration be reported with the Lorenz curve and summarized with the Gini coefficient, and we proposed generalized versions of the Lorenz curve and the Gini coefficient to correct for bias when crime data are sparse (i.e., fewer crimes than places).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proposed generalizations are based on the principle that the observed crime concentration should not be compared with perfect equality, but with maximal equality given the data. The generalizations asymptotically approach the original Lorenz curve and the original Gini coefficient as the number of crimes approaches the number of spatial units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The package goes a bit beyond the method in the published paper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In footnote 3 of our paper we stated that we ignored the bias in the standard Gini because the bias is small in exactly the situations that we were addressing: when # units of analysis is large. However, if there are only a few crimes (and for example all of which are located in one unit), the generalized gini will have quite some bias. In the package, we now also correct for this (using the function argument &lt;code&gt;unbiased&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of the jackknife procedure we briefly discuss in the paper, a bootstrap procedure is implemented to calculate confidence intervals of the Gini. Our reasoning is that the jackknife only leads to a variance that can be used to calculate a standard error, but confidence intervals based on jackknife’s s.e. assume a normal distribution which is very often not the case. Bootstrapping gives correct (parametric or non-parametric) confidence intervals, although the usual caveats apply for small counts. Various options are possible, leveraging the &lt;code&gt;boot&lt;/code&gt; package. Note that one can also automatically plot the distribution of the bootstrap-simulated Ginis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Lorenz plot can be automatically rescaled. This could be more useful when comparing two crime types than the original plots (Figure 3 and Figure 5, right-hand side) in the paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install the package, follow the instructions on its &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wsteenbeek/lorenzgini&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing for similarity in area-based spatial patterns: how the pattern of pedestrian stops by the NYPD differs from crime (2006-2016)</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2018-stlouis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2018-stlouis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social interactions and crime revisited: An investigation using individual offender data in Dutch neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/publication/stats_articles/2017-article-social-interactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/publication/stats_articles/2017-article-social-interactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- More detail can easily be written here using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Micro-Spatial Longitudinal Analysis of Home Burglary Concentration and Spatial Stability in the Context of a Crime Drop</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2017-asc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2017-asc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How businesses and facilities affect crime: a fixed effects analysis of street segments over a ten-year period in The Hague, The Netherlands</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2017-oslo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2017-oslo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open for business: The impact of opening hours on street segment crime levels</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2016-asc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2016-asc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Residential burglary target selection: an analysis using Google maps</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2016-esc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2016-esc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruimtelijk-temporele patronen van woninginbraak in Antwerpen, 2005-2014: In hoeverre is woninginbraak geconcentreerd in bepaalde straatsegmenten, en hoe stabiel is deze concentratie over de tijd?</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2017-nvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2017-nvc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wat maakt het misdaadpatroon: buurt of straat?</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2017-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/talk/2017-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Embed your slides or video here using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/). Further details can easily be added using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code. --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybercriminal decision-making</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/project/cybercrime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/project/cybercrime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Existing theories assume that offenders make rational decisions, but these theories have rarely been tested experimentally. This project uses &amp;lsquo;honey accounts&amp;rsquo;, online accounts that have deliberately been rendered vulnerable to hacking, to allow an experimental investigation of cybercriminals&amp;rsquo; behavior. The research offers unique opportunities for conducting a stringent test of existing criminology theories on offenders&amp;rsquo; decision-making behavior. This study of offender behavior will broaden our understanding of cybercrime, as previous research has tended to focus on victims and security.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Across the Urban Landscape</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/project/risk-urban/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/project/risk-urban/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parameters of Risk Across the Urban Landscape (PRAUL) uses data from multiple years on victimizations, crime risk factors, and victimization surveys to analyze these causal links between criminogeneity, fear of crime, and actual crime for the city of Amsterdam. Spatio-temporal clustering and regionalization procedures are used to identify areas of elevated risk and delineate analytical sub-regions that are as homogeneous as possible for the theoretical constructs of interest. These newly defined areas serve as units of analysis to study the interplay between the purported crime risk factors, crime, and the public’s reaction to crime and policing from a spatio-temporal perspective. The project aims to provide new insights into the relative importance of individual- and area-level causal factors of fear of crime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risky Business</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/project/risky-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/project/risky-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do businesses (e.g. bars or supermarkets) and facilities (e.g. libraries) generate or prevent crime? Urban planners and policy-makers often view businesses and facilities as a panacea to social problems: they create jobs and invest in their buildings and immediate surroundings. In contrast, and supported by most empirical research findings, environmental criminologists argue that crime is more likely to occur near businesses. However, such empirical research is based on cross-sectional data, which allows investigating correlation between businsses and crime. However, correlation does not imply causation. So, should urban planners combine residential and commercial buildings within neighborhoods? This project investigates the causal effect of businesses and facilities on crime using unique longitudinal data and recently developed econometric methods for spatio-temporal analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for a crime</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/project/time-for-crime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/project/time-for-crime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why do offenders commit crimes where and when they do? Improving on extant theory and empirical research in the geography of crime, the proposed PhD-research will investigate how offenders&amp;rsquo; time-specific knowledge of their environment acquired during their daily routines and the time-varying attractiveness of target areas affect offenders’ crime location choices. Combining police-register data on offenders and their offenses with unique data on the locations the offenders frequently visit and data on opening and closing hours of Dutch businesses and facilities, this cutting-edge research project not only advances scientific knowledge, but also contributes to better crime forecasting and urban planning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
