<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>efspi on Kaspar Rufibach</title>
    <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/tags/efspi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in efspi on Kaspar Rufibach</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://numbersman77.netlify.com/tags/efspi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>EFSPI regulatory statistics working group</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/efspi_regstat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/efspi_regstat/</guid>
      <description>The regulatory committee of the European Federation of Statisticians in the Pharmaceutical Industry (EFSPI) co-ordinates regulatory activities across the European Pharmaceutical Statistical community. The key areas of engagement are the Review of regulatory guidance to provide consolidated cross industry responses and identification regulatory statistical issues that are concern across industry for discussion with regulators. In addition, the committee meets yearl with the MHRA biostatistics unit and the EMA biostatistics working part (BSWP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oncology estimand working group</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/efspi_estimand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/efspi_estimand/</guid>
      <description>In February 2018, Evgeny Degtyarev from Novartis and myself started an informal working group to discuss how to implement the ICH E9 draft addendum on estimands in oncological clinical trials.

Goals of the working group Bring together statisticians from industry, regulators, and academia to ensure common understanding and consistent definitions for key estimands in oncology across and share experiences, intercurrent events, and the used sensitivity analyses. Key questions that are discussed are:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>