<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workings on Kaspar Rufibach</title>
    <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workings on Kaspar Rufibach</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>EFSPI regulatory statistics working group</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/efspi_regstat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/efspi_regstat/</guid>
      <description>The regulatory committee of the European Federation of Statisticians in the Pharmaceutical Industry (EFSPI) and PSI co-ordinates regulatory activities across the European Pharmaceutical Statistical community. The key areas of engagement are the Review of regulatory guidance to provide consolidated cross industry responses and identification regulatory statistical issues that are concern across industry for discussion with regulators. In addition, the committee meets yearl with the MHRA biostatistics unit and the EMA biostatistics working part (BSWP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oncology estimand working group</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/efspi_estimand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/efspi_estimand/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAVVY: Survival analysis for AdVerse events with VarYing follow-up times</title>
      <link>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/savvy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://numbersman77.netlify.com/working/savvy/</guid>
      <description>The SAVVY project is a consortium of academic and pharmaceutical industry partners that aims to improve the analyses of adverse event (AE) data in clinical trials through the use of survival techniques appropriately dealing with varying follow-up times and competing events. Although statistical methodologies have advanced, in AE analyses often the incidence proportion, the incidence density or a non-parametric Kaplan-Meier estimator are used, which either ignore censoring or competing events. In an empirical study including randomized clinical trials from several sponsor companies, these potential sources of bias are investigated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>